Michael Wheatman

3116 Carnegie Dr | State College, PA 16803 Phone: (215) 326-9809 E-Mail: michael.wheatman@gmail.com

Summary

I am a software engineer with three years of technology industry experience. I possess a rigorous academic background and strong communication skills. I maintain full time employment as a software developer with a specialization on server side development for wide scale distributed systems.

Experience

Software Engineer - Raytheon Corp.

2015 - Present

- Contributes to active development of classified computer systems for US Government customers. Maintains
 Top Secret/SCI US Government Security Clearance.
- YESNET East Region Director of Communications

Software Development Engineer Intern - Amazon AWS

2014

Worked in AWS Identity and Access Management building an internal registry designed to centralize and organize the metadata and development information for all AWS services and APIs.

Computing Support Assistant - Carleton College ITS

2011 - 2015

Worked to provide technical support to students, faculty, and staff of the College.

Education

Pennsylvania State University - Computer Science (MS - anticipated 2018)

2015 - Present

- Working on degree part-time.
- Thesis: Storage Techniques for Large Scale Distributed Systems.

Carleton College - Computer Science (BA), Cognitive Science (minor)

2011 - 2015

- Served on Library and Information Technology College Governance Committee
- Thesis: Augmented Reality on Mobile Systems.
- Publication:
 - Liking, Defining, and Thinking, Oh My!: Ways of Knowing and Appraisal of Intellectual Activities - Psychonomic Society, 2015

Skills

Cloud Computing Technologies, Full Stack Java Development, Agile Software Development, Python Development, Computer Security, Linear Regression Techniques, Distributed Systems Design and Development, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, SQL and NoSQL Database Systems